Whether you're a beginner in programming or have experience in other languages,
سواء أكنتم مبتدئين في البرمجة أم لديكم خبرة في لغات برمجة أخرى،
this course is well-structured to help you develop fluency in Python.
فإن هذه الدورة مصممة على نحو يساعدكم على إتقان لغة Python.
Each lesson includes videos,
يتضمن كل درس مجموعة من الفيديوهات
text summaries, quizzes and coding activities for each concept.
والملخصات والاختبارات ونشاطات كتابة التعليمات البرمجية لكل مبدأ نتناوله.
If you'd like to move through the course faster,
إذا أردتم التقدم في الدورة بشكل أسرع،
you can skip directly to text summaries and quizzes to test your knowledge,
يمكنكم الانتقال مباشرة إلى المخلصات والاختبارات لاختبار معرفتكم،
and go back to videos if you get stuck.
ثم العودة إلى الفيديوهات إن واجهتم صعوبة.
However, if you are new to programming,
لكن إذا كنتم مستجدين في البرمجة،
I strongly recommend watching the videos for a detailed walk-through of each topic.
فإنني أوصي بشدة بأن تشاهدوا الفيديوهات للحصول على شرح مفصل لكل موضوع.
Here's an overview of what you learn.
إليكم لمحة عامة على ما ستتعلمونه.
You'll start off learning about the basics of python in lesson two;
ستبدؤون بتعلم أساسيات Python في الدرس الثاني،
data types and operators.
أنواع البيانات والمعاملات.
These are the building blocks you use to write your programs.
هذه هي لبنات البناء التي ستستخدمونها في كتابة برامجكم.
In lesson three, you'll dive into control flow tools.
في الدرس الثالث، ستتعمقون في موضوع أدوات تدفق عناصر التحكم.
You learn about conditional statements,
ستتعرفون على العبارات الشرطية،
loops, built-in functions, and list comprehensions.
والتكرارات الحلقية والدوال المضمنة وشمول القوائم.
With control flow tools,
باستخدام أدوات تدفق عناصر التحكم،
you'll be able to write more complex and creative code.
ستتمكنون من كتابة تعليمات برمجية أكثر تعقيداً وإبداعاً.
In lesson four, you'll learn about function definitions, variable scope,
في الدرس الرابع، ستتعرفون على تعريفات الدوال ونطاقات المتغيّرات
documentation, lambda expressions, iterators, and generators.
والتوثيق وعبارات لامبدا والمُكررات والمولّدات.
This is where things can become a little tricky.
هنا قد تصبح الأمور صعبة بعض الشيء،
But these are also some of
لكنها في الوقت ذاته بعض أهم الأدوات
Finally, the last lesson will show you how to run your code
وأخيراً، سيعرض لكم الدرس الأخير كيفية تشغيل التعليمات البرمجية التي تكتبونها
locally and scripts that take in raw input and work with files.
على أجهزتكم والنصوص البرمجية التي تستقبل المدخلات غير المنسقة وتتعامل مع الملفات.
You'll also learn about error handling and importing different libraries.
وستتعرفون أيضاً على معالجة الأخطاء وكيفية استيراد المكتبات المختلفة.
I know this looks like a lot of content,
أعرف أن هذا يبدو كثيراً،
but there's plenty of review and practice
لكننا سنقوم بالكثير من المراجعة والممارسة أثناء الدورة لترسيخ ما ستتعلمه.